WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY. SO
GLASS OF ORANGE JUICE MIGHT BE
SIPPING ON THIS MORNING TO THE
FRUIT IN YOUR FRIDGE, EVEN THE
PRICES AT THE GROCERY STORE.
>> MUCH OF IT AS YOU PROBABLY
KNOW, STARTS IN FLORIDA. BUT
RIGHT NOW NEARLY THE ENTIRE
STATE IS DRYING OUT AND HARSH
WINTER HAS ONLY MADE THINGS
WORSE, PUTTING THOSE FARMERS
UNDER INTENSE PRESSURE
THREATENING CROPS THAT FEED
AND FUEL THE REST OF OUR
COUNTRY. NEWSNATION'S RICK
SHAFFER IS LIVE FOR US IN
MIAMI. LOOK, THEY'RE CALLING
THIS ONE OF THE TOUGHEST
STRETCHES IN DECADES. JUST HOW
SERIOUS IS THIS DROUGHT RIGHT
NOW. EXTREMELY SERIOUS
MARQUIS. IN FACT, IN PARTS OF
THE STATE DESOTO COUNTY JUST
FURTHER NORTH OF WHERE WE ARE
THAT COUNTY IS NOW IN EXTREME
DROUGHT. IT'S ACTUALLY THE
FIRST TIME THAT THAT HAS
HAPPENED SINCE 2001, ACCORDING
TO STATE RECORDS AND THEY ARE
NOT ALONE HERE. IN FACT.
>> ABOUT 95% OF FLORIDA.
ACCORDING TO OFFICIALS, IS NOW
IN MODERATE DROUGHT OR WORSE
WITH CONDITIONS ARRIVING A LOT
EARLIER MONTHS EARLIER. IN
FACT, THE NORMAL STATE
AGRICULTURE OFFICIALS ESTIMATE
RECENT FREEZES AND DRY
CONDITIONS HAVE CAUSED MORE
THAN A BILLION DOLLARS IN CROP
DAMAGE ACROSS FLORIDA AND
MARCIE. THAT IS PROMPTING THE
STATE TO MOVE QUICKLY AS
FA